



Kalaipriya Kannan

Lead SME L&D Data and Reporting | Scrum Master



+91-9840511730



kalaipriya.kannan@gmail.com

Certified Scrum Master and Seasoned Business Analyst offering 9 years of industry success. Expert on business and systems requirements, user acceptance testing and end-user training. Diligent worker with strong communication and task prioritization skills. Worked on diversified portfolio such as Life Sciences, Healthcare, Blockchain Frameworks and L&D Data Reporting. Strong experience in Business Analysis and Data Analysis, proficient in SQL, Tableau.



Skills

Business Need Analysis

Project & Team Management

Project & Team Management

Very Good

Requirement Analysis

Excellent

Data Analysis & Reporting

Very Good

Business Consulting & Advisory

Excellent

Strategic planning

Very Good

Agile Methodologies



Work History

- Carelon Global Solutions, Bangalore
 Acting as lead point of contact for L&D Data and Reporting
- Working in parallel projects (L&D active and Blockchain frameworks shadowing) assisting the leadership in decision making for application deployments
- Created dashboards to monitor and track key performance indicators.
 Generated business intelligence reports to inform strategic decision-making.

2021-04 - Current

2017-05 - 2021-03

- Working with development team to understand technical needs and managed sprint cycle
- Developed business solutions leveraging existing technology to meet requirements of key stakeholders, product leadership teams, and steering committees
- Reporting monthly data analysis findings to leadership to use in making organizational L&D decisions
- Analyzed key aspects of business to evaluate factors driving results and summarized into presentations.
- Improved business direction by prioritizing customers and implementing changes based on collected feedback.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Generated ad-hoc reports to evaluate specific business requirements.
- Supported leadership team with reporting, analysis, and business presentations to inform divisional strategies.
- Lead end-to-end release and implementation life cycles of product enhancements by ensuring project requirements are met with optimal business results

Deloitte USI, Hyderabad

- With strong experience in areas of change and release management, defect analysis, system configuration, stakeholder communication and providing training related to new learning solutions
- Managed team of 6 and acted as escalation point of contact for various learning leads across EMEA and APAC region, directly interact with vendor for any change requests or enhancement requests basis the need
- Collaborated with Project Owners, Project Managers to provide functional release per sprint cycle
- Assisted management with backlog refinement sessions
- Identified and implemented operational improvements, enhancements, customizations and rolling out learning solutions that arise from the need analysis, communications & project management
- Facilitated various user groups meeting with learning leaders across member firms in different geographical regions for best practices and gaining consensus visioning to business growth
- Evaluated staff performance and provide coaching to address inefficiencies. Evaluated customer needs and feedback to drive product and service improvements.
- Created and managed project plans, timelines, and budgets.

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai

- Worked on L&D requirements and delivered to meet client needs for functionality and organization development.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality prior to release.
- Developed need based training modules for developing multi skilled work force and mentored new team members to come up learning curve
- Managed the team of 12 for a large pharmaceutical client in the UK with focus on excelling business targets & service delivery metrics
- Monitored and evaluated metrics, prepared reports on standards & performance target
- Ensured quality services are provided and document functionalities are maintained



Education

2010-08 - 2014-04

B.Tech: Information Technology

Vel Tech Institutions - Chennai



Certifications

- Professional Scrum Master (PSM1)
- Certified Blockchain Expert (CBE)
- Certified Blockchain Developer (CBD)
- IBM Blockchain Essentials
- IBM Certified Big Data and Data Science Foundations
- Scrum Concepts & Product Owner
- Agile Principles & Methodologies



Technical Skills

•

SQL

Tableau

Python

Advanced Excel

HTML

Postman



Tools Worked



Jupiter Notebook

ServiceNow

Salesforce

Remedy

MS SQL Server

Oracle DB



LMS Worked



SuccessFactors

Saba Cloud

Workday

Corner Stone on Demand (CSOD)

Oracle LMS

Plateau



Blockchain Frameworks



Hyperledger Fabric

Ethereum

(Permissioned & Private networks)